Guide to the Irving McNeil Ives papers, 1862-1958
Ives, Irving McNeil papers, 1862-1958
- SERIES I. CORRESPONDENCE and LEGISLATION
  - [U. S. Senate] National Housing Act, S.2246 - 1919-- (Box 215, Folder 27)
    conference comm. print
  - [U. S. Senate] Economic Recovery Program - Original Statement re amendment to reduce appropriation by $500,000 - 5/3/50 S. 3304 - 81st Congress - 1950 (Box 215, Folder 28)
  - [U. S. Senate] Economic Recovery Program Draft of proposed amendment and floor statement suggested by Mr. Rhodes - not used by I.M.I. - S. 3304 - 81st - 1950 (Box 215, Folder 29)
    Economic Recovery Program
  - [U. S. Senate] Defense Production Aid - S. 3936 - 81st - 1950 (Box 215, Folder 30)
    Defense Production Act (1950)
  - [U. S. Senate] Defense Production Act - S. 3936 - 81st - 1950 (Box 215, Folder 31)
    Federal Mediation and Conciliation Service, National Grange
  - [U. S. Senate] Defense Production Act - 1950 (Box 215, Folder 32)
  - [U. S. Senate] Control Legislation - Miscellaneous data on Reference Production Act S. 3936 - 81st - 1950 (Box 215, Folder 33)
  - [U. S. Senate] Appointment- Marshall - Original Statement on George C. Marshall appointment of 9/18/50 - Supporting data - 1950 (Box 215, Folder 34)
  - [U. S. Senate] Reorganization Plan No. 2 - S. Res. 151 - Original Statement in 8/18/49 - Background data - 81st - 1949 (Box 215, Folder 35)
    government reorganization; Maurice S. Tubin statement, Herbert Hoover statement; Buffalo Chamber of Commerce
  - [U. S. Senate] State Department Investigation Minority Report of Subcommittee Investigating McCarthy Charges - S.Res 231 - 81st - 1950 (Box 216, Folder 1)
    subversive elements in government, communism
  - [U. S. Senate] Reorganization Plan no. 12 - NLRB - Original of Statement 5-11-50 - Supporting data S. Res 248 - 81st - 1950 (Box 216, Folder 2)
    government reorganization; Citizen's Comm. for the Hoover Report
  - [U. S. Senate] Reorganization Plan No. 12 - Miscellaneous data - S. Res 248 - 81st - 1949-1950 (Box 216, Folder 3)
    NLRB (proposed reorganization)
  - [U. S. Senate] Subversive Activity - (S. R. 280) - 81st - 1950 (Box 216, Folder 4)
    subversive elements (in government)
  - [U. S. Senate] Equal Rights Amendment - 1949 - Copies of amendments and background data S. J. Res. 25 - 81st - 1945, 1947-1949 (Box 216, Folder 5)
    women's rights; Frances Perkins, Frieda S. Miller
  - [U. S. Senate] S. Con. Res. 2 - 81st Congress. 1st Session Rule making - Relative to reform in procedure before Congressional Committee - 1949 (Box 216, Folder 6)
    rule making (U. S. Congress)
  - [U. S. Senate] S. Con. Res. 20 - 81st - 1949 (Box 216, Folder 7)
  - [U. S. Senate] H. R. 2270 - 1949 (Box 216, Folder 8)
    U. S. Code (crimes and criminal procedure)
  - [U. S. Senate] Displaced Persons - Drafts of statements in re - including Alfange on Greek Children - Misc. data - H. R. 4567 81st - 1949 (Box 216, Folder 9)
    immigration; Dean Alfange
  - [U. S. Senate] Displaced persons - 1950 - Draft of speech by Noblemen dated 8/22/50 - Data for statement of 4/4/40 in H. R. 4567 - 81st - 1949-1950 (Box 216, Folder 10)
    displaced persons; Hubert Humphrey
  - [U. S. Senate] Social Security H. R. 6000 - Misc. data - 81st - 1950 (Box 216, Folder 11)
    Marion B. Folsom; Civil Service Employees Assoc. Inc.
  - [U. S. Senate] H. R. 9176 - 81st Congress - 1950 (Box 216, Folder 12)
    control legislation, Defense Production Act
  - [U. S. Senate] I.M.I. - 81st 1 - 1949 (Box 216, Folder 13)
    U. S. Senate (voting compilation)
  - [U. S. Senate] I.M.I. - 81st 2 - 1950 (Box 216, Folder 14)
  - [U. S. Senate] Legislation sponsored or co-sponsored by I.M.I. - 82nd Congress - 1951-1952 (Box 216, Folder 15)
  - [U. S. Senate] Discrimination in Armed Services - S-1 - 1951 (Box 216, Folder 16)
  - [U. S. Senate] Price Controls - S. 1717 and others - 82nd - 1951 (Box 216, Folder 17-18)
  - [U. S. Senate] Immigration - S. 2550 & S. 2842 - 82nd - 1952 (Box 216, Folder 19)
  - [U. S. Senate] S. 3368 Prohibit Discrimination in Employment (82nd) - see S. 692 - 82nd - 1952 (Box 216, Folder 20)
  - [U. S. Senate] Troops to Europe - S. Res. 99 - 82nd - 1951 (Box 216, Folder 21)
    foreign affairs
  - [U. S. Senate] S. Res 203 - 82nd - 1952 (Box 216, Folder 22)
    U. S. Senate (rules and administration), cloture rule (U. S. Senate)
  - [U. S. Senate] 82nd Congress - Reorganization Plans - S. Res 317, 331, 330 - 1952 (Box 216, Folder 23)
    government operations (reorganization)
  - [U. S. Senate] H. R. 385 - Highland Falls, (St. George) - 82nd - 1951 (Box 216, Folder 24)
    Highland Falls, N. Y. (land acquisition); Katherine St. George
  - [U. S. Senate] H. R. 911 - 82nd - To appoint male citizens as nurses in Army, Navy, Air Force? - 1950 (Box 217, Folder 1)
    armed services (personnel); Frances D. Bolton, M. D.
  - [U. S. Senate] Public Law 590 - 82nd Congress H. R. 7800 - 1952 (Box 217, Folder 2)
    social security
  - [U. S. Senate] H. R. 4473 - 82nd - 1951 (Box 217, Folder 3)
    retirement funds
  - [U. S. Senate] Response to I.M.I. Affirmative Vote in McGuire Fair Trade Bill - July 1952 - 1952 (Box 217, Folder 4)
    fair trade legislation
  - [U. S. Senate] I.M.I. - 82nd - 1 - 1951 (Box 217, Folder 5)
  - [U. S. Senate] I.M.I. - 82nd - 2 - 1952 (Box 217, Folder 6)
  - [U. S. Senate] S. 655 - 59 - 83rd - 1953 (Box 217, Folder 7)
    labor-managment relations
  - [U. S. Senate] S. 692. To prohibit discrimination in Employment - Labor - 1953-1954 (Box 217, Folder 8)
    labor (legislation); Walter White (NAACP), Paul H. Douglas
  - [U. S. Senate] Hearings - S. 692 - 1st - 1954 (Box 217, Folder 9)
    discrimination, labor (legislation); Franklin Roosevelt, Jr., Eugene Carson Blake; American Friends Service Committee
  - [U. S. Senate] Hearings - S. 692 - 2nd - 1954 (Box 217, Folder 10)
    discrimination, labor (legislation); Walter Reuther; National Urban League, YWCA, AFL
  - [U. S. Senate] I.M.I. - 1954 (Box 217, Folder 11)
    discrimination, labor (legislation); Leverett Saltonstall; National Council of Negro Women, American Veterans Comm., Catholic Interracial Council
  - [U. S. Senate] S. 692 Hearings - Correspondence with members of the Sub-committee to hold these hearings - 1953-1954 (Box 217, Folder 12)
    labor (legislation); Wayne Morse, Herbert Lehman, Hubert Humphrey, H. Alexander Smith
  - [U. S. Senate] I.M.I. - 1954 (Box 217, Folder 13)
    discrimination, labor (legislation); R. C. A., American Council on Human Rights
  - [U. S. Senate] S. 692 Hearings - Misc. 1. clippings, 2. lists of those invited to hearings and correspondence re such hearings, 3. etc. - 1953-1954 (Box 217, Folder 14)
    discrimination, labor (fair employment practices)
  - [U. S. Senate] Controls Legislation - S. 753 - 1953 (Box 217, Folder 15)
    economic controls (legislation); economy (controls)
  - [U. S. Senate] S. 975 - Maybank and Capehart - To Amend Home Owners Act - 1954 (Box 217, Folder 16)
  - [U. S. Senate] S. 1068 - Co-sponsor (Sen. Griswold) - to provide hospital care and medical treatment for certain disabled veterans. Labor - 83rd - 1953 (Box 217, Folder 17)
  - [U. S. Senate] S. 1069 - Co-sponsor (Sen. Grisold) - Provide further opportunity for veterans of WW II under the Servicemen's Readjustment Act of 1944 - Labor - 1953 (Box 217, Folder 18)
  - [U. S. Senate] S. 1075 I.M.I. Amend Title II of the Taft-Hartley Act with respect to settlement of labor disputes resulting in national emergencies (see S. 1026) - Labor - 83rd - 1953 (Box 217, Folder 19)
    labor management relations, strikes
  - [U. S. Senate] S. 1081 - Co-sponsor (Sen. Capehart) Banking - to provide authority for temporary economic controls - 1953 (Box 217, Folder 20)
    economic controls (temporary); Homer E. Capehart
  - [U. S. Senate] S. 1523 and other bills (S. 892, 1559, 1771, 1907, 1912, 1913, and H. R. 5141) 83rd, B & C - 1953 (Box 217, Folder 21)
    small business (legislation), B & C (legislation)
  - [U. S. Senate] S 1746 Ferguson - Judiciary - To Assist in relieving immigration and refugee problem by issuance of 240,000 special visas in 1953-1954 - 1953 (Box 217, Folder 22)
  - [U. S. Senate] S. 1864 - I.M.I. - To amend Housing Act of 1949 - B & C (note - see S. 2103) - 1953 (Box 217, Folder 23)
    housing, federal aid (housing); Robert Moses
  - [U. S. Senate] S. 1866 - I.M.I. - Labor-Amendment Fed. Food, Drug, Cosmetic Act to identify aureomycin as chlortetracycline - 1953 (Box 217, Folder 24)
    drug (naming)
  - [U. S. Senate] S. 1917 - Watkins, et al - J C - 240,000 special immigrant visas to certain escapees, German expellees, nationals of Italy, Greece and Netherlands - 1953-1954 (Box 217, Folder 25)
    immigration (legislation); American Legion
  - [U. S. Senate] S. 2047 - Amend Rubber Act of 1948 - 1953-1954 (Box 217, Folder 26)
    rubber (producing facilities), rubber (plant disposal); Homer Capehart
  - [U. S. Senate] S. 2346 - I.M.I. - Authorize army to convey certain lands to St. Regis Paper Co. - Armed Services - 83rd - 1953-1954 (Box 217, Folder 27)
    land (transfer)
  - [U. S. Senate] S. 2383 - Henrickson, et al - Bill granting consent of Congress to a compact between N. Y. and N. J. known as the Waterfront Compact - 83rd - 1953 (Box 218, Folder 1)
    waterfront compact (N. Y.?N. J. compact); Thomas E. Dewey (telegram)
  - [U. S. Senate] S. 2474 - Lehman and I.M.I. - To authorize coinage of 50-cent pieces to commemorate tricentennial of NYC - B & C - 1953-1954 (Box 218, Folder 2)
    currency; Homer E. Capehart, Sidney A. Fine, Charles A. Buckley
  - [U. S. Senate] S. 2477 - Dirksen, et al - J C - To amend Trading with the Enemy Act (re. Gen. Aniline) - 1953 (Box 218, Folder 3)
    foreign policy (legislation)
  - [U. S. Senate] S. 2672 - [1953] (Box 218, Folder 4)
  - [U. S. Senate] S. 2758 - Smith (I.M.I.) Medical Facilities Survey and Construction Act - Medical facilities (construction) - 1954 (Box 218, Folder 5)
  - [U. S. Senate] S. 2759 - Smith (I.M.I.) Vocational Rehabilitation Amendments - Labor - 83rd - 1954 (Box 218, Folder 6)
  - [U. S. Senate] S. 2763 - Hill (I.M.I. co-sponsor) - Interior To amend Outer Continental Shelf Lands Act in order to provide revenues for grants in aid for education - 1954 (Box 218, Folder 7)
  - [U. S. Senate] S.2802 - Saltonstall (I.M.I. co-sponsor) Interstate - Bill to encourage distribution of fishery products - 83rd - 1954 (Box 218, Folder 8)
    Leverett Saltonstall, John Kennedy
  - [U. S. Senate] S.2846 - 83rd - 1954 (Box 218, Folder 9)
    Securities Exchange Act
  - [U. S. Senate] S. 2910 - 3 additional judges for southern District and one for the Eastern District - J C - 1953-1955 (Box 218, Folder 10)
    judgeships (creation)
  - [U. S. Senate] Housing Act - S. 2938 and H. R. 7839 - 83rd - 1954 (Box 218, Folder 11)
  - [U. S. Senate] Housing Act - 1954 (Box 218, Folder 12)
  - [U. S. Senate] S. 2938 - Housing Act - 1954 (Box 218, Folder 13)
    Albert M. Cole (statement)
  - [U. S. Senate] Housing Act - H. R. 7839 - 1954 (Box 218, Folder 14)
  - [U. S. Senate] Housing Act - 1954 (Box 218, Folder 15)
    Wm. J. Levitt
  - [U. S. Senate] Comparative Analysis of Testimony on the Housing Act (S. 2938) - 1954 (Box 218, Folder 16)
  - [U. S. Senate] Stichman, Herman T. Commission of Housing, Annual Report, 1954. "Our Cities, Our Children, and the Future" - 1954 (Box 218, Folder 17)
    housing (N. Y. S)
  - [U. S. Senate] S. 3114 - 1954 (Box 218, Folder 18)
  - [U. S. Senate] S. 3271 - Smith, N. J. - Vocational Education Act - 1954 (Box 218, Folder 19)
    education (vocational)
  - [U. S. Senate] S. 3291 - I.M.I. - Authorizing the Pres. to present a gold medal to Irving Berlin - B & C - 1954 (Box 218, Folder 20)
    awards, Bernard M. Sharley
  - [U. S. Senate] S. 3628 - Upton (I.M.I. et al) Amend. To P L 815, 81st Congress, to provide School construction - (Labor), 83rd - 1954 (Box 218, Folder 21)
    education (federal aid)
  - [U. S. Senate] S. 3706 - Subversive Activities Control Act - I.M.I. Amendment - 83rd - 1954 (Box 218, Folder 22)
    subversive activities (legislation)
  - [U. S. Senate] S. Res 25 - Re Export-Import Bank - 1952-1953 (Box 218, Folder 23)
    foreign investments (study of)
  - [U. S. Senate] S. Res 70 - For. Rel. - Co-Sponsor (Sen. Murray) Condemns revival of Anti-Semitism in Russia and her Satellite countries - 1953 (Box 218, Folder 24)
  - [U. S. Senate] S. Res 84 For. Rel. - Amendment - Willey?I.M.I. amended this bill 2-27-53 - 1953 (Box 218, Folder 25)
    Russia (minority group treatment)
  - [U. S. Senate] S. Res 229 - Capehart - (I.M.I., et al) - B&C - To authorize the Comm. on B & C to investigate housing - 1954 (Box 218, Folder 26)
    housing (federal programs), housing (investigation)
  - [U. S. Senate] S. Res 260 - Lehman (I.M.I.-Kennedy) - C A S - To suspend transfer of Quarter-master Purchasing Ag. From NYC to Philadelphia - 83rd - 1954 (Box 218, Folder 27)
    U. S. Army (Quartermaster Procurement Center)
  - [U. S. Senate] S. J. Res 1 - J C - Amend. To Constitution relative to making of treaties and exec. Agreements - 1953-1954, 1956 (Box 219, Folder 1)
    treaty-making (constitutional amendment); Pat McCarran, John Brinker
  - [U. S. Senate] S. J. Res #1 - 1953 (Box 219, Folder 2)
    foreign affairs (Treaties); John W. Brinker
  - [U. S. Senate] Amendment to S. J. Res. 13 - I.M.I. - to confirm and establish titles of the states to lands beneath navigable waters within state boundaries and to natural resources within such lands and waters - 83rd - 1953 (Box 219, Folder 5)
    tidelands
  - [U. S. Senate] S. J. Res 26 - B & C - To extend certain authority of the Federal Nat. Mortgage Assoc. and Fed. Housing Administration to Guam - (note - see S. J. 71) - 1953 (Box 219, Folder 6)
    Federal National Mortgage Association
  - [U. S. Senate] S. J. Res. 27 - Capehart - To amend section 2 (a) of the National Housing Act as amended B & C - 1953 (Box 219, Folder 7)
    home improvement (loans)
  - [U. S. Senate] S. J. Res 66 - I.M.I. - J C - Making available certain unused immigration quota numbers for assignment by the President - 1953 (Box 219, Folder 8)
    immigration (legislation); Dwight D. Eisenhower
  - [U. S. Senate] S. J. Res 71 - I.M.I. - To extend certain authority of the Fed. Nat. Mortgage Association to Guam and to amend Nat. Housing Act with respect to housing in Alaska - B & C - 1953 (Box 219, Folder 9)
  - [U. S. Senate] S. J. Res 74 - J C - Recognition of the 200th Anniversary of the Founding of Columbia University - 83rd - 1953 (Box 219, Folder 10)
    Columbia University (Bi-centennial)
  - [U. S. Senate] S. J. Res. 76 - I.M.I. - Designating Week 6/14/53 as 'The Roosevelt Week' - J C - 83rd - 1953 (Box 219, Folder 11)
  - [U. S. Senate] S. J. Res 77 - F. R. - I.M.I. - Amend joint resolution of 6/16/30 creating the Niagara Falls Bridge Commission - 1953 (Box 219, Folder 12)
  - [U. S. Senate] S. J. Res 99 - I.M.I. - Celebration of 200th Anniversary of the Congress of 1754 - J C - 83rd - 1953 (Box 219, Folder 13)
    Lea W. O'Brien
  - [U. S. Senate] S. J. Res 140 - Mundt (I.M.I., et al) - Establish commission for celebration of 200th birthday - Alex Hamilton - J C - 83rd - 1954 (Box 219, Folder 14)
    Karl E. Mundt
  - [U. S. Senate] S. J. Res 173 - I.M.I. - J C - To designate National Salvation Army Week - 83rd - 1954 (Box 219, Folder 15)
  - [U. S. Senate] S. Con. Res. #81 - I.M.I. - Felicitating NYS and its Board of Regents - J C - 83rd - 1954 (Box 219, Folder 16)
  - [U. S. Senate] H. R. 459 - Congressman Kearney - (Misc. Public Bills) - 83rd Congress - 1954 (Box 219, Folder 17)
  - [U. S. Senate] H. R. 1357 - Congressman Multe - To confer jurisdiction on the District Court of Northern District of Ill. - 1953-1954 (Box 219, Folder 18)
    U. S. Congress (court jurisdiction)
  - [U. S. Senate] H. R. 5173 - Congressman Reed (Misc. Public Bills) - 83rd - 1953 (Box 219, Folder 19)
    employment security financing
  - [U. S. Senate] H. R. 5407 - 83rd Congress - 1954 (Box 219, Folder 20)
    internal revenue code
  - [U. S. Senate] H. R. 5420 - Congressman Keating - to amend Sec. 161, title 35, U. S. Code, Relating to patenting of plants - 83rd - 1954 (Box 219, Folder 21)
    patents; Kenneth Keating
  - [U. S. Senate] H. R. 5740 - 83rd Congress - 1953 (Box 219, Folder 22)
    pharmacy (inspection)
  - [U. S. Senate] H. R. 6049 - Congressman Kearns - To provide assistance in construction of school facilities - 83rd - 1953 (Box 219, Folder 23)
  - [U. S. Senate] H. R. 6113 - Congressman Dorn to amend U. S. Code - 1954 (Box 219, Folder 24)
    customs service
  - [U. S. Senate] H. R. 6130 Mrs. St. George - to permit a first preference for former owners of certain dwellings having sold under the Lanham War Housing Act - 1953-1954 (Box 219, Folder 25)
  - [U. S. Senate] H. R. 6185 - Congresswoman St. George - to amend vet preference Act 1944 - P L 271 - 83rd Congress - 1953 (Box 219, Folder 26)
    veteran affairs
  - [U. S. Senate] H. R. 6440 - 83rd Congress - 1954 (Box 219, Folder 27)
    income tax code
  - [U. S. Senate] H. R. 6456 - Congressman Sadiale - Provides 35% advalorem tax (on American selling price thereof) on footwear, the soles of which are made of Indian rubber - 1953 (Box 219, Folder 28)
  - [U. S. Senate] H. R. 6657 - 83rd Congress - 1954 (Box 219, Folder 29)
    education (vocational rehabilitation); National Federation of the blind
  - [U. S. Senate] H. R. 6988 - Mrs. St. George - to direct Sec. Of the Army to establish national cemetery in Rockland Co., N. Y. - 1953-1954 (Box 219, Folder 30)
    cemeteries (national)
  - [U. S. Senate] H. R. 7488 - Congressman Williams - Retirement by Banks of Certain Preferred Stock - 1954 (Box 219, Folder 31)
    U. S. I. R. Service
  - [U. S. Senate] H. R. 8041 - Congressman Rudwon - Provide benefits based upon service in WAAC under certain conditions - 1954 (Box 219, Folder 32)
    WAAC (benefits)
  - [U. S. Senate] H. R. 8100 - Congressman Wharton - To amend Agri. Act of 1949 to provide for sale of surplus grains to farmers - 1954 (Box 219, Folder 33)
    agriculture (legislation)
  - [U. S. Senate] H. R. 8300 - Senate Finance Committee - 1954-1955 (Box 219, Folder 34)
    taxation (income tax)
  - [U. S. Senate] Internal Revenue Code of 1954? - 1954 (Box 219, Folder 35)
  - [U. S. Senate] H. R. 8873 - Lehman (I.M.I. and Kennedy) - Appro. Amend re Transfer to quartermaster Dn. Agency from NYC to Philadelphia - 83rd - 1954 (Box 219, Folder 36)
    appropriations (U. S. Govt.)
  - [U. S. Senate] H. R. 9366 - I.M.I. Amend. To Soc. Sec. Act and Int. Rev. Code to extend coverage under old age and survivors insurance program - 1954 (Box 219, Folder 37)
  - [U. S. Senate] H. R. 9859 - 83rd - 1954 (Box 219, Folder 38)
    public works (flood control)
  - [U. S. Senate] S. Res 31 - Amend. To Rule XXII of Senate R. C. - 83rd - 1952-1954 (Box 219, Folder 39)
    U. S. Senate (internal affairs), Cloture (U. S. Senate)
  - [U. S. Senate] Rule XXII - Senate - background Data (1/53) - 1953 (Box 219, Folder 40)
    U. S. Senate (internal affairs), U. S. Senate (standing rules - debate)
  - [U. S. Senate] Private and Public Bills - 84th Congress - I.M.I. - 1955-1956 (Box 219, Folder 41)
  - [U. S. Senate] S. 67 Amendments to Dirksen (I.M.I.) PO & CC - To adjust compensation of Federal employees - 1955 (Box 219, Folder 42)
    federal employees (benefits)
  - [U. S. Senate] S. 372 Bridges (I.M.I., etc.) P. O. & C. S. - For payment of annuities to widowers of female employers who die in service - 1954-1955 (Box 219, Folder 43)
    Retirement Federation of Civil Service Employees
  - [U. S. Senate] S. 413 Smith (N. J.) (I.M.I. et al) For. Rel. - For relief of Ref. and Counsel Comm. of Foreign Missions Conf. - 1955 (Box 219, Folder 44)
  - [U. S. Senate] S. 414 Bush (I.M.I., et al). LPW. Survey and examination of coastal and tidal areas of U. S. re hurricanes - 1955 (Box 219, Folder 45)
    hurricanes (early detection)
  - [U. S. Senate] S. 519 - I.M.I. (Saltonstall, Case) - Immigration and Nationality Act - J C - I - 1955-1956 (Box 219, Folder 46)
    immigration laws (U. S.); Anti-defamation League of B'nai B'rith
  - [U. S. Senate] S. 519 - I.M.I. (Saltonstall, Case) - Immigration and Nationality Act - J C - II - 1955-1956 (Box 219, Folder 47)
    immigration laws (U. S.); Herbert Lehman
  - [U. S. Senate] S. 519 - I.M.I. (Saltonstall, Case) - Immigration and Nationality Act - J C - III - 1957 (Box 219, Folder 48)
    immigration laws (U. S.)
  - [U. S. Senate] S. 657 - I.M.I. (Butler, Case) - Interstate and Foreign Comm. - Discrimination in Interstate Transportation - 1955 (Box 219, Folder 49)
    Warren Magnuson; NAACP
  - [U. S. Senate] S. 669 Neely (I.M.I., etc.) - To provide home rule for the District of Columbia - 1955 (Box 219, Folder 50)
  - [U. S. Senate] S. 732 ?I.M.I. (Lehman) - Interior and Insular - Rehabilitation and preservation of nations, important historic properties - 1954-1955 (Box 219, Folder 51)
    historic preservation (NYC); Robert Dowling, Robert F. Wagner, Guy Gordon; Downtown Manhattan Association
  - [U. S. Senate] S. 755 - 84th - Sale of housing projects in Virginia - 1955 (Box 220, Folder 1)
    U. S. Senate - 84th Congress - housing (legislation); Subcommittee of the Committee on B & C - Hearing
  - [U. S. Senate] S. 772 Hill (I.M.I., et al) To amend Outer Continental Shelf Lands Act - Interior and Insular - 1955 (Box 220, Folder 2)
    oil (for education); Lister Hill
  - [U. S. Senate] S. 886/S. 929 - Nurses training - 1955 (Box 220, Folder 3)
  - [U. S. Senate] S .899 - To prohibit discrimination in employment because of race, color, religion, national origin or ancestry - 1955 (Box 220, Folder 4)
  - [U. S. Senate] S. 928 Kuchel (etc.) - Pub. Works Water Pollution Control Act - 1955 (Box 220, Folder 5)
    water pollution; Thomas H. Kuchel
  - [U. S. Senate] S. 967 Lehman (I.M.I., etc.) - To provide for maintenance and Merchant Marine Academy - Interstate For. Comm. - 1955 (Box 220, Folder 6)
    Estes Kefauver
  - [U. S. Senate] S. 994 Thye (I.M.I.) - To suspend for one year certain duties upon importation of aluminum - F C - 84th - 1st - 1955 (Box 220, Folder 7)
    tariff legislation
  - [U. S. Senate] S. 1048 - Federal Aid Highway Act - Public Works - 1955 (Box 220, Folder 8)
  - [U. S. Senate] S. 1151 Watkins (I.M.I., etc.) - Illegal Employment of Aliens Act of 1955 - J C - 1955 (Box 220, Folder 9)
    immigrant labor
  - [U. S. Senate] S. 1152 Watkins (I.M.I., etc.) - Illegal Transportation of Aliens Act - J C - 1955 (Box 220, Folder 10)
  - [U. S. Senate] S. 1501 Capehart (I.M.I., etc.) - C A S Housing Insurance Act - B & C - 1955 (Box 220, Folder 11)
  - [U. S. Senate] S. 1886 I.M.I. (Lehman) - Provides for Jurisdiction and interest over Ellis Island to N. Y. S. - J C - 1955 (Box 220, Folder 12)
    Ellis Island, New York, surplus government property (U. S)
  - [U. S. Senate] S. 2113 Watkins (I.M.I., etc.) To amend the Refugee Relief Act of 1953, as amended - J C - 1955 (Box 220, Folder 13)
    immigration (U. S.); Wm. Langer
  - [U. S. Senate] S. 2142 Lehman (I.M.I., et al) - J C - To amend Act of 7/1/52 - To obtain consent of Congress re interstate compacts - 84th 1st - 1955 (Box 220, Folder 14)
    civil defense; Herbert H. Lehman
  - [U. S. Senate] S. 2179 - I.M.I. To incorporate the National Academy of Design - J C - 84th - 1955 (Box 220, Folder 15)
    National Academy of Design; Frederic R. Coudert, Jr.
  - [U. S. Senate] S. 2183 - I.M.I. - Extend unemployment compensation program to Puerto Rico - F C - 84th - 1st - 1955-1956 (Box 220, Folder 16)
    unemployment compensation
  - [U. S. Senate] S. 2379 Payne (I.M.I., etc.) - Provides for training of needed personnel for fishing industry - Interstate and For. Com. - 84th - 1st - 1955-1956 (Box 220, Folder 17)
    fisheries (personnel); Frederick G. Payne